BRANDON JARVINEN

Santa Cruz, CA

brandon.jarv@gmail.com



PERSONAL FOCUS

I take pleasure in creating tools for easy tweaking of gameplay mechanics, to produce highly refined and exciting games. I am an avid eSport enthusiast who enjoys competing in game tournaments for games such as Smash Bros Melee, Dota 2, and Counter-Strike: Global Offensive. My love for eSports has led me to create experiences that can be enjoyed with friends.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages and tools: C++, C#, Python, Unity, Visual Studio, Git, HTML5, Monodevelop, Javascript Academic Subjects: Game Design Process, Scrum/Agile, Game AI, Comparative Programming Languages, Data Structures, Debugging, Database Design, Web Apps, Arduino

PROJECT HIGHLIGHTS

Engine Programmer - Birds at Arms - (12/2015-Current) Nominated for Technical Achievement Casual 2D MOBA built with a custom engine using SDL, including networking and animations.

- Engine built from the ground up, dynamically loads resources and uses object pooling.
- Packaged network packets for syncing game state among up to 8 players on Steam.
- Runner-up for the 2016 Sammy Awards Technical Achievement Award at UC Santa Cruz.
- Take a look at the Github Repository

Gameplay/Lead Programmer - PROJECT HYPETRAIN, with Ursa Major Games, an indie dev project (04/2014 - 09/2015)

- In C# and Unity, implemented BFS companion AI, gun kickback which gives the player aerial mobility, in-game menus, shop system, as well as train car and item spawning.
- Create programming team sprint tasks as well as manage bug reports for the project.
- Check out our site or Github Repository

Network/Gameplay Programmer - KrabKlashers - (Winter 2015)

3D Online Multiplayer Arena Combat game made utilizing the SCRUM methodology. Made with Unity3D using Photon Unity Networking.

- Implemented player movement, combat system with melee, dash attacks, and parrying.
- Used Photon for chat, and game room systems as well as syncing data for scoreboard.
- Take a look at the Github Repository

Engine Programmmer - IncognitOwl - (Winter 2014)

In a world of Patriot Owls vs Soviet Bats, only the IncognitOwl can infiltrate the bat base and retrieve the intelligence needed to win the war.

- Using HTML5 canvas and Javascript, implemented collision detection, character movement, and level creation.
- The game is playable in a browser and saves progress as you complete levels.
- Play the game here or check out our Git.

EXPERIENCE

Instructor - Stanford University ID Programming Academy Programming Instructor for C++ and Unity/C#. (06/2015 - 08/2015)

- Taught groups of 8 to 16 students in C++ and Unity/C# on 2D game development and practices.
- Developed lesson plans for a wide range of skill sets and debugged multiple projects written in different languages.

VEX Robotics 3rd Place Winner in World Championship - (09/2008 - 04/2011)

- Attended the VEX World Championships three times, placing 3rd in 2011 as well as 5th in 2010.
- Awarded three Programming Division Champion awards for my autonomous routines in C.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science: Computer Game Design

University of California, Santa Cruz